{"data":[{"question":"Your son ________ morning exercises everyday.","a":"do","b":"does","c":"is doing","d":"are doing","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Your son + singular verb","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Tomorrow ________ my friend's birthday. I ________ some flowers for her.","a":"is \/ will buy","b":"will be \/ will buy","c":"is \/ buy","d":"will be \/ buy","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Speakers occasionally use Simple Present to talk about scheduled events in the near future.\u00a0\n- Simple future: often suggests that a speaker will do something at the time of speaking","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"It's often warm ________ summer and cool ________ autumn.","a":"in \/ on","b":"one \/ in","c":"in \/ in","d":"at \/ in","answer":"3","explain":"- We use In as a preposition before seasons (summer, autumn...)","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Her birthday is ________ August the third. She always gets a lot of presents ________ her birthday.","a":"on \/ on","b":"in\/ in","c":"on \/ in","d":"in \/ at","answer":"1","explain":"\n- On: for specific day and dates (on Sunday, on 6 March, on Christmas Day, on my birthday...).\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Joseph\u00a0is learning English ________ his room and his dog is ________ the desk.","a":"at \/ in","b":"at \/ on","c":"in \/ on","d":"in \/ under","answer":"4","explain":"\nPrepositions of Place: at, in, on, between, over, into.\n- At for a point: at the corner, at the bus stop, at the door, at the top of the page, at the front desk...\n- In for an enclosed space: in the garden, in London, in a box, in my wallet, in a industry...\n- On for a surface: on the wall, on the floor, on a page...\n- Under: below or at a lower level than something, or covered by something","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Are you free ________ today, Paul? No, I am very busy ________ the housework.","a":"in \/ with","b":"on \/ of","c":"no word \/ with","d":"at \/ to","answer":"3","explain":"\n- We don't use preposition before \"today, yesterday, next week...\".\u00a0\n- Busy with something.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Bob, would you like to go ________ the zoo ________ us on Sunday. - I'd love to, but I am afraid not because I have a lot of exercises to do.","a":"with \/ to","b":"to \/ with","c":"to \/ to","d":"no word \/ with","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Go to somewhere with somebody.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Thanks ________ ringing. I am going to see you at half ________ seven.","a":"of \/ to","b":"for \/ to","c":"for \/ past","d":"of \/ over","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Thanks somebody for doing something.\u00a0\n- Past (prep): later than a particular time.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Rebecca is English but she isn't ________ England. She comes to Vietnam ________ Thailand.","a":"from \/ in","b":"from \/ for","c":"for \/ from","d":"from \/ from","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Come from somewhere: used for stating someone's origin","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"},{"question":"Look ________ that strange man. He is looking ________ Lan but Lan isn't here.","a":"for \/ at","b":"at \/ for","c":"at \/ at","d":"after \/ at","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Look at somebody = see.\u00a0\n- Look for= search\/find.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"17","subcategorylv2":"13","type":"1"}]}